Commanders family, welcome in the free
agency Fridays. We are here in the Big
Bear AI Command Center studio for a
special version of Next Man Up. We have
possibly the most exciting signing of
Free Agency. Chickquila in the building.
Got the dreads hanging. My boy feeling
good. First things first, brother.
Congratulations, man. This is a big
deal.
>> Yeah, I appreciate it, man. Thank you so
much. It's a dream come true.
>> Yeah, dream come true and a welcome home
kind of man. Former Maryland Turk, man.
Back in the DMV, man. What's it feel
like to be back? You caught some snow
today.
>> Hey, they told me it was 85.
>> It was yesterday. I promise it was. I
promise.
>> And I come in and it's snowing. I'm
like, March. I don't remember Maryland
being like like the DMV area being like,
"There's not a March." But yeah, man.
I'm super excited to be back, bro. Super
excited to be a commander and just uh
get this thing going.
>> I mean, they say rain, snow, it's
supposed to be a sign of good luck. So,
maybe it's just a sign of good fortune
headed your way as you rock the Burgundy
and Gold. Can we call it that? That's
exactly what we're going to go with.
We're running with We're running with
that one.
>> We love that chick. Now, I'm going to be
honest with you, man. A lot of teams was
looking at you. You're a very, very
talented tight end coming off of a
career year. What makes you say, "I want
to go be a commander?"
>> Uh, man, the the culture,
the Q,
like just there's just pieces, you know,
all around that like just can't ignore.
I feel like this team's just they need
one little thing, a little spark, you
know, to get them over that edge. And I
feel like I could be that guy. So, I
feel like it's just a no-brainer, you
know, coming back to DMV too and put on
for the home team. Like, why not?
>> I got to imagine this is a little
surreal for you. Like I said, you played
over at Maryland just right up the way
>> and you told me before we started,
there's 32 seasons in the NFL. You
didn't know where you'd end up, but it's
got to be kind of wild to be back in the
DMV, especially having played at
Maryland.
>> It is wild. And my first ever college
game was actually in uh
>> Wow. It's now Northwest Stadium.
>> Was in Washington Stadium. Yeah. Against
Texas. So yeah, it is surreal, man, to
come back and, you know, be here.
>> And like I described it, it really still
hasn't even fully hit me yet. Like,
dang, I'm I'm a commander.
>> Why?
>> I'm in Washington. Like,
>> I mean, this is the first for you,
right? Because you're drafted by the
Titans. You're there your whole career,
four years. This is a first step for you
being able to
>> see what your market's like. Go three
free agency. Man, did you have a little
fun in this process? Cuz I got to
imagine it's kind of nice having people
throwing dollars at you,
>> bro. It wasn't It wasn't fun at all,
bro.
>> Yeah.
Bro, it wasn't fun at all, bro. It was
an anxiety like
>> just days of anxiety cuz I I thought my
deal was going to be done quick.
>> You know, I'm seeing everyone else get
their done deal their deal done pretty
quick. Mine was like, you know, after 48
hours, I'm over there like, man, like
every time the phone rings, I'm I'm
answering. I'm like, man, what are they
talking about? You know, hear this from
this team, hear this from that team. And
then you finally get on with the
commanders and um we just clicked. What
they talked about, what I talked about,
it just married up together and here I
am now.
>> I'm glad you put it like that.
>> Signed.
>> I'm glad you put it like that cuz like
fans, they're stressed and they're
anxious like waiting to see who's going
to get signed. But I don't think they
think about the player also waiting
letting your agents do all that
negotiating. That's a lot.
>> They Yeah. They can they can't even
imagine, bro. Like it's literally felt
like it felt like draft night again.
>> Yeah. Really? that that intense.
>> Yeah, it felt like dropped down again
because you're just sitting there like
ah what's going on? And then you the
phone ring. It's not what you wanted to
hear or it is what you wanted to hear
but it's not what you wanted to hear.
And then it's like dang and you got your
boys calling like what's going on? You
got everyone in the fam like was like I
remember my my family didn't want to
text. Like I didn't get a call from my
sisters or my mom the whole days cuz
they was just as nervous.
>> Yeah. So then when I called them and I
told them, they were like, "Oh my god,
you don't understand how anxious we've
been
>> and I'm like, "Yeah, I could imagine.
Y'all imagine how I've been feeling."
But yeah.
>> Well, hey, no more reason for anxiety.
You here now. You're home now, man. It's
great to have you here. And it's
especially great to have you here
because again, like I said, you're
coming off a career year. So, I want to
look at last year real quick and ask you
what went right for Chig last year. Why
do you feel you were able to really put
more things together and have a good
year? It's funny that that that that was
a career year because it just feels like
to me it just felt like I was doing like
the bare minimum.
>> Wow. Really? That's why when my I
remember uh when coach um told me at the
end of the year, "Oh, you just broke
your uh like record receptions." I was
like, "Dang, really?" Cuz I it felt like
I wasn't even touching the ball till
like week week 10, week nine. So, um
yeah, I feel like for me there's just so
much more there's just so much more I'm
I'm able to do. That's why one of the
things here coming here too, they're
seeing the the how the the offensive
leaders of this team just like they see
the role that they see me playing. I'm
just so excited, bro, to just know like
I'm a featur I'm going to be a featured
guy from the first week.
>> I can't imagine I can't even imagine
like what my numbers would look like if
I was getting real real targets from
week one where I was running real routes
from week one. I'm telling y'all, bro,
the potent like I'm excited, bro.
>> I I can see the chip on your shoulder
right now.
>> I'm excited, bro. I'm excited to finally
show exactly what Chico Conco is
supposed to look like on a football
field for a whole season.
>> I love that, man. I love that. And you
mentioned the conversations you're
having with the coaching staff with
ownership and all that stuff.
>> You said something clicked. What were
those things that clicked to you where
they were saying the right things and
you were like, "Okay, this is the home
for me." I think the number one thing
for me that I loved about when I, you
know, had my call, you know, with the
staff was the first thing they said was,
"We love the way that you play." And
that was one thing for me. I was like, I
want I want someone to like appreciate
the way that I play the game. Like,
appreciate that how tough I am and
appreciate that. And just to see them
that that that was the first thing that
and then the first like the clips that
he's showing me like he start showing me
clips and the clips that he's showing me
are like my I'm not even getting the
ball. It's like when they throw a pick
and it's like how hard I'm running to
tackle
>> to tackle like the um the guy who caught
the pick or something and I'm like man
they see that
>> I'm like bro I'm like I'm so happy like
there there's a team out there who
actually sees this like they see the dog
like they see the dog mentality when I
play. Like they're telling me we love
the way you play with the ball in your
hands. I'm like okay finally a team that
sees this. like I'm not running out of
bounds. I'm not ducking smoke from
nobody. Like like I'm really I'm I'm
really about that and I'm I'm so glad
that they see it. And as soon that that
what really made me feel good cuz for
more so for me it's like that's my
mentality.
>> Yeah.
>> That's my that's my play style. Like
regardless of running routes, catching
touchdowns, all that stuff for coach to
validate the effort and the the way that
you play, I really love that honestly.
And that was really the main thing for
me coming here.
>> And check, I'm not gonna lie, you might
have broke some news to the fan base
because you said you gonna be a premier
option on this offense. Not a lot of
people get that check right away and
say, "Hey, we going to use you a lot."
What is that conversation like? Whether
it's with David, David Blau, whether
it's with DQ, who is that one telling
you like, "Hey man, this is what we're
going to do with you here."
>> So really all of them. All of them, they
just they know they have a they have a
they have a specific vision for me.
>> I mean, I can tell that they're very
smart coaches. they they can they they
see it on tape. They're like, "Man, if
he was on our team doing this, then he
would be able to do go crazy." And it's
like he's showing me like clips of the
tight ends and the offense they run. I'm
just like, "Whoa, look at all that. That
space is insane." Like, I haven't seen
space like that past four years my
career. And just having Jaden on the
field, too, a quarterback that can run,
have these all these mismatches that
teams are going to have to to look at.
Like I said, bro, the potential is
there. Like the sky's is the limit is
there. So excited to get going, bro.
Like like you said, a chip on my
shoulder, bro. I got a I got a chip on
my shoulder this year for sure. Like
they got to feel me, bro. I love that.
They got to feel you, man. And
>> it's a big moment for you to be coming
here because we know what year three is
like for any athlete, let alone a
quarterback. And now Jaden Daniels is
about to be in year three. They bring
you in and say, "Hey, you're going to be
a big weapon for him." How can you help
Jaden as he develops through this third
year? How can you help this offense and
help us be more dynamic?
>> Man, I'm want to be that spark plug,
bro. Like the guy that that's just a
playmaker.
>> And it don't need to be from me running
a route, cooking somebody, and catching
the ball 50 yards down the field. Like,
you can give me the ball on a screen and
I'll take it 50.
>> You can give me the ball on a screen.
You can give me the ball on on a flat.
I'll make the first guy miss, make the
second guy miss, do something with it.
And I feel like that's what this team is
just um been needing is just that that
spark. The guy that can do it at any
point like on the field like five yard
stick that might go for 20
>> whereas someone else he's getting
tackled like five yard route I might
make that 15 17. Does those little
things add up over the course of a game
that's that's that's what I'm bringing
to his offense.
>> And it's wild to think because you only
been in the league four years. You're a
very young man, but you come into a
tight end room where you one of the
veterans, right? We got guys younger
than you. Are you excited for that
leadership role as well, that mentorship
role for guys like Ben Sinnate who want
to be on that chig level, who want to
get that big contract, man? Are you
excited for that leadership part of
this?
>> Yeah, definitely. Um, being a guy now,
being a guy now as a second contract
guy, you know, I feel like I have to uh
step into a mature a more mature role on
the team, you know, be someone that
speaks up more like guys are going to be
looking, you know, for that as a guy who
has been paid. Um, definitely I am super
excited, you know, being in that role.
So I was kind of in that role last year
was like the most oldest most
experienced guy in my room last year. So
um definitely it's definitely cool to
just mentor young guys, bro, all the
time. It's definitely cool. Like they're
they're your brother. Like why would you
not help them? So yeah, excited to help.
>> And chick, my last question. I feel like
you might have already answered it, man.
What is your goals for yourself in this
season right here? Your first one with
the burgundy.
>> First one, bro. I want to uh I want to
unlock unlock my full potential, bro.
That's simply it. I want to look back on
the tape and be like, "Yeah, I'm doing
things that that I'm excited to do."
Like, coach coach is letting me do
things I'm excited to do. Coach letting
me do things that are tailored to my
talent. Like, coach understands my
talent and he lets me go out there and
show it on the field. I'm not about to
be he's not going to make me just sit
there and, you know, chip and go to the
flat for the whole game. It's going to
be a scheme play for me and I'm going to
take that scheme and I'm going to put it
on the field.
>> My boy salivating on that field. You
ready, man? You got me ready. You're
like, "Dang, listen. The season's
starting now. Come, this is what free
agency Friday is all about. Getting to
know these guys." And Chick, we are so
happy to have you, man. The fan base,
I'm sure, is already blowing you up.
Just excited to have you in the
building. And again, my brother, welcome
back home.
>> Hey man, thank you so much, man. I
appreciate you guys. Thank you for
having me, dog. Can't wait to get it
going. Hey, DMV, we up.
>> We up, Commanders P. This is the free
Fridays, official version of Next Man Up
with our newest premier tight end, my
boy Chick. Thank you, brother. Yes, sir.
Appreciate you,